export const data= [
    {
        question: "Linear search is also called------",
        option1: "Random Search",
        option2: "Sequential search",
        option3: "Perfect search",
        option4: "None",
        ans: 2,
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is correct recurrence for worst case of Binary Search?",
        option1: "T(n) = 2T(n/2) + O(1) and T(1) = T(0) = O(1))",
        option2: "T(n) = T(n-1) + O(1) and T(1) = T(0) = O(1)",
        option3: "T(n) = T(n/2) + O(1) and T(1) = T(0) = O(1)",
        option4: "T(n) = T(n-2) + O(1) and T(1) = T(0) = O(1)",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "Given a sorted array of integers, what can be the minimum worst-case time complexity to find ceiling of a number x in given array? The ceiling of an element x is the smallest element present in array which is greater than or equal to x. Ceiling is not present if x is greater than the maximum element present in array. For example, if the given array is {12, 67, 90, 100, 300, 399} and x = 95, then the output should be 100.",
        option1: "O(loglogn)",
        option2: "O(n)",
        option3: "O(log(n))",
        option4: "O(log(n) * log(n))",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "Consider a sorted array of n numbers and a number x. What would be the time complexity of the best known algorithm to find a triplet with sum equal to x. For example, arr[] = {1, 5, 10, 15, 20, 30}, x = 40. Then there is a triplet {5, 15, 20} with sum 40.",
        option1: "O(n)",
        option2: "O(n^2)",
        option3: "O(n*logn)",
        option4: " O(n^3)",
        ans: 2,
    },
    {
        question : "Number of comparisons required for an unsuccessful search of an element in a sequential search, organized, fixed length, symbol table of length L is",
        option1:"L",
        option2:"L/2",
        option3:"(L+1)/2",
        option4:"2L",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question : "What are the advantages of Linear Search Over Binary Search?",
        option1: "The array is ordered.",
        option2: "Less number of comparison",
        option3: "less time and space complexity",
        option4: "Linear search can be used irrespective of whether the array is sorted or not",
        ans: 4,
    },
    {
        question: "Suppose there are 11 items in sorted order in an array. How many searches are required on the average, if binary search is employed and all searches are successful in finding the item?",
        option1: "3.00",
        option2: "3.46",
        option3: "2.81",
        option4: "3.33",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question : "The necessary condition for using binary search in an array is :-",
        option1: "The array should not be too long",
        option2: "The array should of more size",
        option3: "The array should be sorted",
        option4: "None of these",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "The time taken by binary search algorithm to search a key in a sorted array of n elements is",
        option1: "O(log2n)",
        option2: "O(n)",
        option3: "O(nlog2n)",
        option4: "O(n^2)",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "The increasing order of performance  of the searching algorithms are:",
        option1: "linear search  <  jump search  <  binary search",
        option2: "linear search  >  jump search  <  binary search",
        option3: "linear search  <  jump search  >  binary search",
        option4: "linear search  >  jump search  >  binary search",
        ans: 1,
    },
];